Guide to the Louise Seaman Bechtel Papers, 1877-1980 (bulk 1913-1980)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. AUTHOR/ILLUSTRATOR/PUBLISHER FILES
  - SIMON, John Allsebrook
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Folder 38.577)
  - SLAUGHTER, Gertrude
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 38.578)
  - SLOANE, William
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Folder 38.579)
  - STEFANSSON, Vilhjalmur and Evelyn (later Mrs. John U. Nef)
    - Correspondence from VS, 1923-1961 (Folder 38.580)
    - Christmas cards from VS, 1942-1956 (Folder 38.581)
    - Correspondence from Evelyn Stefansson Nef, 1963-1964 (Folder 38.582)
    - Christmas cards form ES Nef, 1970-1971, n.d. (Folder 38.583)
    - Greetings from ES Nef, n.d. (Folder 38.584)
    - Correspondence from John Nef, plus card, 1965-1966 (Folder 38.585)
    - Note from Evelyn Stefansson and copy of LSB's letter to her included with program of memorial service for Vilhjamur Stefansson. (Found together), 1962 (Folder 38.586)
    - Correspondence about VS from William Robbins and Erica Parmi, 1964-1975 (Folder 39.587)
    - Page from Dictionary catalog of the Stefansson Collection on the Polar Regions - Dartmouth College Library, n.d. (Folder 39.588)
    - Writings by VS, 1920, 1945 (Folder 39.589)
    - Writings by VS, 1954, n.d. (Folder 39.590)
    - Articles about, and notes by LSB, 1961-1962, n.d. (Folder 39.591)
    - Misc. article with note from LSB, 1974 (Folder 39.592)
    - Photographs, 1928, n.d. (Folder 39.593)
  - STEVENS, Wallace
    - Correspondence to Ned and Louise, 1943-1948 (Folder 39.594)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Folder 39.595)
    - Christmas card, ca. 1953 (Folder 39.596)
    - Correspondence from Elsie Stevens (WS's wife), 1960 (Folder 39.597)
    - Correspondence from Holly Stevens (WS's daughter), 1963-75, n.d. (Folder 39.598)
    - Ned Bechtel's notes on WS including carbon copies of letters to WS and Mrs. Stevens and to George Martin of the Century Association, 1951, 1947-1950, 1955, 1955 (Folder 39.599)
    - Correspondence about WS from Samuel Morse - also carbons of materials sent to Mr. Morse by LSB (letters from WS), Feb-Mar 1960 (Folder 39.600)
    - Correspondence about WS, 1955-1959 (Folder 39.601)
    - Typed catalogue of books, letters, memorabilia from Bechtel's library given to Amherst College, as of 1963 (Folder 39.602)
    - LSB's notes, n.d. (Folder 40.603)
    - Poem by WS published in Harper's Bazaar, ca. 1948 (Folder 40.604)
    - Articles about, 1950-1954 (Folder 40.605)
    - Articles about, 1954-1955 (Folder 40.606)
    - Articles about, 1956-1966 (Folder 40.607)
    - Articles about, 1967-1974 (Folder 40.608)
    - Article about WS by his daughter, Holly, 1971 (Folder 40.609)
    - Advertisement for TV program on WS, n.d. (Folder 40.610)
    - Historical Review of Burke County, WS Memorial Issue, 1959 (Folder 40.611)
    - Photos and negatives, 1954 (Folder 40.612)
  - STRYKER, Lloyd Paul
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Folder 40.613)
    - Articles about, 1955 (Folder 40.614)
  - TAYLOR, Francis Henry
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Folder 40.615)
  - TAYLOR, Katherine
    - Correspondence, 1960-1975. n.d. (Folder 40.616)
    - Christmas cards, 1937, 1962 (Folder 40.617)
    - Correspondence about KT, 1964 (Folder 40.618)
    - Copy of foreword for Buried Cities by Jennie Hall, written by KT, n.d. (Folder 40.619)
    - Articles by KT with note by LSB, 1964, n.d. (Folder 40.620)
  - TEASDALE, Sara
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Folder 41.621)
    - Christmas cards, ca. 1920s (Folder 41.622)
    - Photos (Teasdale file includes photographs of Vachel Lindsay), ca. 1920s (Folder 41.623)
  - THURSTON, Ada
    - Correspondence [fragment] (Folder 41.624)
  - VAN LOON, Hendrik Willem [See also Series VI for artwork by Van Loon.]
    - Correspondence, 30 Aug 1941 (Folder 41.625)
    - Christmas cards, ca. 1920s, 1932 (Folder 41.626)
    - Articles about - one regards his death, the other is a review of "The Story of Hendrik Willem Van Loon" written by his son, 1944, 1972 (Folder 41.627)
    - Articles about - with explanantory notes by LSB, 1932 (Folder 41.628)
    - Photographs, ca. 1930s (Folder 41.629)
  - VLARNER, Velma
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 41.630)
  - WALKER, Dugald Stewart
    - Correspondence (Folder 41.631)
    - Original drawing - chapter heading for The Girl Who Sat by the Ashes by Padraic Colum, 1919 (Folder 41.632)
    - Original drawing - Chapter heading for The Girl Who Sat by the Ashes, 1919 (Folder 41.633)
    - Original drawing from The Girl Who Sat by the Ashes, 1919 (Folder 41.634)
    - Original drawing from The Girl Who Sat by the Ashes, 1919 (Folder 41.635)
    - Original drawings, n.d. (Folder 41.636)
  - WARD, Lynd and May (McNeer) [See also Series VI for artwork by Ward.]
    - Correspondence from LW, 1934-1971 (Folder 42.637)
    - Correspondence from MW, 1951-1969, n.d. (Folder 42.638)
    - Greeting cards, 1933, n.d. (Folder 42.639)
    - Greeting cards, n.d. (Folder 42.640)
    - Greeting cards, n.d. (Folder 42.641)
    - Daughter's wedding announcement and card for Prince Bantam, 1966, n.d. (Folder 42.642)
    - Short Biography of May and Lynd Ward put out on publishing co. (Folder 42.643)
    - Articles by LW including his Caldecott Award acceptance, 1931-1964 (Folder 42.644)
    - Article by May McNeer about LW, 1955 (Folder 42.645)
    - Article about LW, 1973 (Folder 42.646)
    - Invitation to an exhibition of lithographs by Lynd Ward, 1961, 1939, n.d. (Folder 42.647)
    - Blurbs about books by MMW and LW (Folder 42.648)
    - Book Collector's Exchange List featuring LW's Madman's Dream, n.d. (Folder 42.649)
    - Published drawing, n.d. (Folder 42.650)
    - Book featuring murals done by LW for the United Methodist Bldg. in Evanston, Illinois, ca. 1969 (Folder 42.651)
    - LSB's notes on LW, n.d. (Folder 42.652)
    - Photographs of daughter Nanda Ward, Lynd and May Ward at Mt. Kisco, ca. 1930s (Folder 42.653)
    - Photograph of LW, ca. 1953 (Folder 42.654)
  - WEISGARD, Leonard
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 43.655)
    - Article by, 1960 (Folder 43.656)
  - WHITE, E.B. and Katherine
    - Correspondence from EBW, Nov, ca. 1945 (Folder 43.657)
    - Correspondence from KW, 1941-1953 (Folder 43.658)
    - Correspondence from KW, 1953-1960 (Folder 43.659)
    - Correspondence from KW, 1961-1970 (Folder 43.660)
    - Correspondence from KW, 1970-1972 (Folder 43.661)
    - Correspondence from KW, 1974, n.d. (Folder 43.662)
    - Christmas and New Year's cards (Folder 43.663)
    - Carbon copies of letters from LSB and her secretary, 1973 (Folder 43.664)
    - Correspondence about EBW to LSB includes material written about Charlotte's Web, 1950 (Folder 43.665)
    - Material writen by EBW, 1960-1975, n.d. (Folder 43.666)
    - Articles about EBW, 1970-1980, n.d. (Folder 43.667)
    - Articles about EBW with notes by LSB, 1976 (Folder 43.668)
    - Articles written by KW, 1959 (Folder 44.669)
    - Articles about KW, 1979 (Folder 44.670)
    - Copies of poem by EBW, "Home Song,", 1944 (Folder 44.671)
    - Publicity put out by publishing company - 2 separate (same ltr. inside), n.d. (Folder 44.672)
    - Advertisements for books by EBW, 1962, 1970, 1977 (Folder 44.673)
    - The William Allen White Children's Book Award, Bronze Medal Awarded to EBW for The Trumpet of the Swan, n.d. (Folder 44.674)
  - WICKENDEN, Dan
    - Correspondence, 1954-1956, n.d. (Folder 44.675)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 44.676)
  - YOUNG, Ella
    - Correspondence including LSB's rewritten copy of the first letter of the series, 1942-1956 (Folder 44.677)
    - Notes by LSB, n.d. (Folder 44.678)
    - Articles about, ca. 1957 (Folder 44.679)
  - MISCELLANEOUS BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Business Correspondence (misc.), 1932-1975 (Folder 44.680)
- SERIES II. BECHTEL PROFESSIONAL and PUBLISHING FILES
  - Manuscripts of LSB Writings
    - "How Three Presbyterian Dolls Came To Live In a Book Room,", 1963 (Folder 45.681)
    - "The Marvellous [sic] Story of Good Saint Florentin of Alsace,", n.d. (Folder 45.682)
    - "My Miss Kate" [about Kate Glendinning Wanvig (VC 1901)] (Folder 45.683)
    - "X-Rays on the Great: A Christmas Fantasy,", ca. 1920 (Folder 45.684)
    - Scripts of the [WJZ's] Story Book Lady, 1924 (Folder 45.685)
    - Speech at New York Public Library's Children's Room, 1939 (Folder 45.686)
    - Speech at meeting of the Women's National Book Association, New York Chapter, 1963 (Folder 45.687)
    - Deletions from a speech on G. Norell's 12-year survey, n.d. (Folder 45.688)
    - LSB notes, n.d. (Folder 45.689)
    - Program for speech given by LSB at the Grolier Club, 1953 (Folder 45.690)
  - Bechtel Publications
    - "Adventures in Making Books," Vassar Quarterly, Nov 1932 (Folder 45.691)
    - A Fair Start, New York Kindergarten Association, ca. 1939 (Folder 45.692)
    - "Honor Bertha Mahony," Top of the News, Oct 1959 (Folder 45.693)
    - Articles in The Horn Book, 1925-1938 (Folder 45.694)
    - Articles in The Horn Book, 1940-1963 (Folder 45.695)
    - "Thinking About Children's Classics," The Packet, Fall 1955 (Folder 45.696)
    - "Margery Williams Bianco," Young Wings [fragment], Oct 1936 (Folder 45.697)
    - "Notes on Children's Books," Vassar Quarterly, May 1920 (Folder 45.698)
    - Vassar Miscellany articles, 1913, 1915 (Folder 45.699)
    - Miscellaneous articles, clippings relating to LSB's career, 1928-1984 (Folder 46.700)
  - The Macmillan Company
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Folder 46.701)
    - Correspondence between LSB and Suzanne Wallace[grad. student] re: Bechtel-created "Little Library" series, 1975 (Folder 46.702)
    - Paper of Suzanne Wallace: "Louise Seaman Bechtel and the Little Library,", 1975 (Folder 46.703)
    - Invitation to Children's Book Dept.'s 50th Anniversary celebration, ca. 1969 (Folder 46.704)
    - Letterhead stationery of Louise Seaman, ca. 1920s (Folder 46.705)
    - Catalog: A Book List for Boys and Girls, 1920 (Folder 46.706)
    - Catalog: Books for Boys and Girls; orig. in Folder 46., [1926] (Folder 46.706f)
    - Catalog: Books for Boys and Girls, 1928 (Folder 46.707)
    - Catalog: The Macmillan Children's Classics, [1928] (Folder 46.708)
    - Catalog: Macmillan Books for Boys and Girls, 1930 (Folder 46.709)
    - "Ladder Books,", n.d. (Folder 46.710)
    - Dummy copy of The Older Children's Bible, 1927 (Folder 46.711)
    - "The Louise Seaman issue" of The Horn Book, Aug 1928 (Folder 47.712)
    - Macmillan children's book ads and reviews in The Horn Book, 1928-1946, n.d. (Folder 47.713)
    - Macmillan children's book brochures, 1967, 1969, n.d. (Folder 47.714)
  - The New York Herald Tribune Book Review
    - Correspondence, 1950-1954 (Folder 47.715)
    - Bechtel book lists, ca. 1950s (Folder 47.716)
    - Bechtel book reviews [Incomplete: see boxes for additional reviews.], 1948-1958 (Folder 47.717)
    - Spring Book Festival announcements [See also box], ca. 1950s (Folder 47.718)
    - Spring Book Festival clippings, ca. 1950s (Folder 47.719)
    - "25 Years Ago," New York Herald Tribune Books [25th anniversary issue], Sept 1949 (Folder 47.720)
  - New York Times
    - Bechtel book reviews [Incomplete. See also "The Book of Louise Seaman at Work"(scrapbook) -- box 63.], 1934-1940 (Folder 47.721)
  - The Louise Seaman Bechtel Children's Book Collection
    - Bookplates of the Bechtel Children's Book Collection, n.d. (Folder 47.722)
    - "Mr. Winkle Moves to Vassar," Vassar Quarterly [For bust of Mr. Winkle, see box 79; for drawing of Mr. Winkle, see framed pencil drawing by Bert Stewart.], Spr/Summ 1981 (Folder 47.723)
    - Program for "An Editor's Round Table" and book exhibit list, 1981, 1986 (Folder 47.724)
- SERIES III. SECONDARY MATERIALS ON PUBLISHING and LITERATURE
  - Awards (Folder 48.725)
  - Bibliographies and book lists (Folder 48.726)
  - Children's collections in various repositories (Folder 48.727)
  - Children's literature (Folder 48.728)
  - Children's literature (Folder 48.729)
  - Folklore, fairytales (Folder 48.730)
  - Robert Frost (Folder 48.731)
  - The Horn Book calendar, 1958 (Folder 48.732)
  - The Horn Book calendar, 1963 (Folder 49.733)
  - The Horn Book calendar, 1965, 1975 (Folder 49.734)
  - Carl Larsson (Folder 49.735)
  - Vachel Lindsay [See also Lindsay photos in box] (Folder 49.736)
  - Literature in general (Folder 49.737)
  - Miscellaneous authors, publishers, librarians (Folder 49.738)
  - Miscellaneous periodicals (Folder 49.739)
  - Pinochio (Folder 49.740)
  - Beatrix Potter (Folder 49.741)
  - Publishing (Folder 49.742)
- SERIES IV. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - ABBOTT, Samuel and Edith
    - Correspondence, 1964-1968, n.d. (Folder 50.743)
    - Newspaper clipping, 1964 (Folder 50.743)
  - ADAMS, Brooks
    - Copies of a letter sent to BA from LSB and letters to LSB from BA - includes cover letter to Amherst librarian written by LSB, 1919-1920 (Folder 50.744)
  - ADAMS, J. Donald
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Folder 50.745)
  - ADAMS, Katherine
    - Correspondence (Folder 50.746)
  - ADSHEAD, Betty
    - Correspondence (with enclosure), 1952-1974 (Folder 50.747)
    - Typescript of speech, n.d. (Folder 50.748)
  - ALDRICH, Donald B.
    - Correspondence from and about newspaper clippings and memorial service program, 1961, n.d. (Folder 50.749)
  - ALLEN, Frederick Lewis
    - Clipping and photograph, 1954, n.d. (Folder 50.750)
  - ANDREWS, Mary Evans
    - Card, 1961 (Folder 50.751)
  - ARMSTRONG, Helene
    - Correspondence (Folder 50.752)
  - ARMSTRONG, Margaret
    - Christmas card and clipping, 1944, n.d. (Folder 50.753)
  - AVERY, George (and Virginia)
    - Correspondence and Christmas card, 1966-1972 (Folder 50.754)
  - AYARS, Rebecca Caudill
    - Correspondence, 1949-1954 (Folder 50.755)
  - BADER, Barbara
    - Correspondence from and about, 1976, n.d. (Folder 50.756)
    - Article, 1972 (Folder 50.757)
  - BATCHELDER, Mildred
    - Correspondence including Christmas card, 1966-1975 (Folder 50.758)
    - Correspondence written and dictated by LSB to MB, 1987-1983 (Folder 50.759)
  - BAYNES, Ernest
    - Photograph, n.d. (Folder 50.760)
  - BECKER, David
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 50.761)
  - BENNETT, Richard
    - Woodcuts, n.d. (Folder 50.762)
  - BENSON, Stella
    - Correspondence, 1925, n.d. (Folder 50.763)
    - Article, 1941 (Folder 50.764)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 50.765)
  - BEROL, Alfred
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Folder 50.766)
  - BLOCH, Lucienne
    - Correspondence (including Christmas card), 1949-1968 (Folder 51.767)
  - BRONSON, Wilfrid Swancourt
    - Correspondence, 1929 (Folder 51..768)
  - BURNS, Aubrey
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Folder 51.769)
  - CARLSON, Natalie
    - Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Folder 51.770)
    - Christmas cards, 1960, n.d. (Folder 51.771)
  - CARRINGTON, FitzRoy
    - Christmas cards, 1938-1940 (Folder 51.772)
  - CARTER, Helene
    - Christmas card and clipping (Folder 51.773)
  - CASE, Josephine
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 51.774)
  - CHAPPELL, Warren
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 51.775)
  - CHASE, Virginia
    - Correspondence, 1953-1969, n.d. (Folder 51.776)
    - Christmas cards, Valentine card, 1973, n.d. (Folder 51.777)
  - CHILDS, Mary
    - Correspondence, 1965, n.d. (Folder 51.778)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 51.779)
  - CHURCH, Barbara
    - Correspondence, 1949-1954 (Folder 51.780)
    - Christmas and Valentine greetings, 1954-1956, n.d. (Folder 51.781)
  - COLLIN, Hedvig
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 51.782)
  - CROWLEY, Mude
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Folder 51.783)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 51.784)
  - D'AULAIRE, Edgar Parin and Ingri
    - Greeting cards, birth announcement, published speech and article, 1939, 1940, 1972, n.d. (Folder 51.785)
  - DAVIDSON, Robert
    - Correspondence, 1962-1974 (Folder 51.786)
  - DAVIS, Lavinia and Wendell
    - Correspondence and Christmas card, 1948-1952 (Folder 51.787)
  - DAVIS, Mary Gould
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 51.788)
  - DAVIS, Peggy (Marguerite)
    - Christmas cards, Correspondence about, ca. 1962-1967, 1971 (Folder 51.789)
  - DE ANGELI, Marguerite
    - Correspondence, Christmas card, articles, 1963, 1974, 1975, n.d. (Folder 52.790)
  - DEMOS, Jean
    - Correspondence, 1960-1976 (Folder 52.791)
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 52.792)
    - Christmas cards, 1971-1975 (Folder 52.793)
  - DESMOND, Alice and Tom
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 52.794)
  - DIX, Beulah (Flebbe)
    - Correspondence, photograph, 1925, n.d. (Folder 52.795)
  - DOMBROWSKI, Katharina
    - Correspondence, carbon of letter sent to Macmillan, 1936-1948 (Folder 52.796)
  - DREA, Helena Chase and William
    - Christmas card, 1971 (Folder 52.797)
  - DUFF, Annis
    - Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Folder 52.798)
  - DUNCOMBE, Fran
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 52.799)
  - DUNN, Kitty
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 52.800)
  - DURAND, Ruth Sawyer
    - Correspondence, article (Folder 52.801)
  - EIFERT, Virginia
    - Correspondence, [1956] (Folder 52.802)
  - ENRIGHT, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence (Folder 52.803)
  - EVANS, Ernestine
    - Correspondence (Folder 52.804)
    - Correspondence about, memorial announcement and obituary, 1945-1967 (Folder 52.805)
  - FANCHIOTTI, Margherita
    - Correspondence about, 1954 (Folder 52.806)
  - FENNER, Phyllis
    - Correspondence, 1957-1978 (Folder 52.807)
  - FERRIS, Helen
    - Correspondence, 1931-1960 (Folder 52.808)
  - FIELD, Elinor
    - Correspondence, ca. 1969 (Folder 52.809)
  - FINLEY, John
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Folder 52.810)
  - FITZHUGH, William
    - Christmas card, 1974 (Folder 52.811)
  - FLEXNER, Jeannie
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 52.812)
  - FORD, Jasmine Britton
    - Christmas card, correspondence, 1971, Feb-May 73 (Folder 52.813)
  - FORD, Lauren
    - Card, article, 1963, n.d. (Folder 53.814)
  - FOSDICK, Raymond
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, 1928-1968 (Folder 53.815)
  - FOWLER, C.
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 53.816)
  - FOX, Helen
    - Correspondence and Christmas card, ca. 1948, n.d. (Folder 53.817)
  - FRICK, Helen
    - Correspondence, articles, 1952, 1965-1967 (Folder 53.818)
  - GAGLIARDO, Ruth
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 53.819)
  - GANNETT, Lewis (and Ruth)
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, assorted cards, articles, 1958, 1966, n.d. (Folder 53.820)
  - GARLAND, Hamlin
    - Photos, ca. 1927-1928 (Folder 53.821)
  - GILDERSLEEVE, Virginia
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 53.822)
  - GILLIES, Alcista
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Folder 53.823)
  - GODWIN, Edward
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 53.824)
  - GREEN, Irene
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, 1948, 1961 (Folder 53.825)
  - GRISWOLD, Erwin
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 53.826)
  - GUTHRIE, Stuart and Eunice
    - Christmas card (photograph), 1975 (Folder 53.827)
  - HACKETT, Frances
    - Correspondence, articles, 1962-1971, n.d. (Folder 53.828)
  - HADER, Berta and Elmer
    - Get Well card (book), n.d. (Folder 53.829)
  - HARLAN, John and Ethel
    - Correspondence and articles, 1963-1965 (Folder 53.830)
  - HAVILAND, Virginia
    - Correspondence, Book of cards, 1963-1975 (Folder 54.831)
  - HAWKINS, Quail
    - Correspondence, article, 1959-1976 (Folder 54.832)
  - HESS, Fjeril
    - Correspondence, conference programs, 1961-1964 (Folder 54.833)
  - HEWINS, Caroline
    - Photograph, biography, 1959, n.d. (Folder 54.834)
  - HILL, Helen and Violet Maxwell
    - Photograph and catalogue, 1937 (Folder 54.835)
  - HITCHINGS, Sinclair
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 54.836)
  - HOCKSIE
    - Correspondence (Folder 54.837)
  - HODGE, Betsy and Philip
    - Correspondence, 1965-1974 (Folder 54.838)
  - HOFER, Philip
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Folder 54.839)
  - HOWE, Becky
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Folder 54.840)
  - HUFSTADER, Alice Anderson
    - Correspondence (Folder 54.841)
  - HULTZ, Helen
    - Correspondence (Folder 54.842)
  - HUNT, Rachel
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Folder 54.843)
  - HUNTTING, Henry
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Folder 54.844)
  - HURD, Clement
    - Correspondence, 1963, n.d. (Folder 54.845)
  - HUTCHENS, John
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Folder 54.846)
  - HYATT, Mary
    - Christmas and birthday cards (Folder 54.847)
  - INGALLS, Fay
    - Correspondence, August 1938 (Folder 54.848)
  - ISHU, Momoko
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 55.849)
  - IZARD, Anne
    - Correspondence, Christmas card, copy of letter, 1967-1972, 1975, n.d. (Folder 55.850)
  - JACOBS, Flora Gill
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Folder 55.851)
  - JAY, Pierre
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Folder 55.852)
  - JONES, Elizabeth Orton
    - Imprint: Oregon - published letter and essays about, 1974 (Folder 55.853)
  - JONES, Rufus
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Folder 55.854)
  - JORDAN, Alice
    - Correspondence, article, 1934-1957, 1976 (Folder 55.855)
  - KAYNOR, Fy
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Folder 55.856)
  - KERR, Sophie
    - Correspondence, article, 1951, n.d. (Folder 55.857)
  - KING, Hortense
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 55.858)
  - KING, Margaret (Peg) and Stanley [See also Series VI for photographic portrait of Peg King.]
    - Correspondence, "Daphne" as nickname for LSB, 1948-1955 (Folder 55.859)
    - 85th birthday card to Peg King with postcards to LSB enclosed. Also photograph, 1961-1963, n.d. (Folder 55.860)
  - KING, Richard
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 55.861)
  - KNOWLTON, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Folder 55.862)
  - KRAUSS, Ruth
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 55.863)
  - LANE, Allen and H.F. Paroissien
    - Christmas card, 1951 (Folder 55.864)
  - LANE, Margaret
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 55.865)
  - LATHAM, Harold
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, Photographs, article, 1965-1967, 1969, n.d. (Folder 55.866)
  - LAWSON, Robert
    - Photograph, 1953 (Folder 55.867)
  - LEAVITT, Margaret (Peg)
    - Correspondence, carbon of letter to Elizabeth Coatsworth, 1979 (Folder 55.868)
  - LEGRAND, Edy
    - Article about, 1943 (Folder 55.869)
  - LEROY, Andre (Eugenie)
    - Greeting card, n.d. (Folder 55.870)
  - LEWIS, Allen
    - Greeting card, articles, 1933, n.d. (Folder 56.871)
  - LEWIS, C.S.
    - Article, Information Sheet, 1964, n.d. (Folder 56.872)
  - LIBBY, Margaret
    - Correspondence, Christmas card (Folder 56.873)
  - LINES, Kathleen
    - Christmas card, 1952 (Folder 56.874)
  - LIVSEY, Rosemary
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, photographs, 1934-n.d. (Folder 56.875)
  - LLAODATH, Henry
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Folder 56.876)
  - LOCKWOOD, Sally
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Folder 56.877)
  - LOWRIE, Rebecca
    - Correspondence, 1936-1968, n.d. (Folder 56.878)
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 56.879)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 56.880)
  - LUNT, Storer
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 56.881)
  - LYMAN, Belgy
    - Correspondence, 1968-1976 (Folder 56.882)
  - MCAFEE, Helen
    - Correspondence, 1931-1949 (Folder 56.883)
  - MACAULAY, David
    - Event Announcement, 1979 (Folder 56.884)
  - MCCLOSKEY, Geneva
    - Card, 1945 (Folder 56.885)
  - MACCRACKEN, Henry Noble
    - Correspondence, 1950, 1960 (Folder 56.886)
  - MCELDERRY, Margaret
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Folder 56.887)
  - MCGREGOR, Della
    - Correspondence, Christmas card, Calendar of Exhibits - Children's Book Fair, 1940, 1952, n.d. (Folder 56.888)
  - MCKEON, M. M. (Edie)
    - Correspondence, Christmas card, 1973, 1975 (Folder 56.889)
  - MACRAE, Julia
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 56.890)
  - MALON, Mary
    - Correspondence, ca. 1957 (Folder 56.891)
  - MANNING, Jackie
    - Greeting card, 1975 (Folder 56.892)
  - MARKHAM, Virgil
    - Photograph, n.d. (Folder 56.893)
  - MARSHALL, Donald
    - Christmas card, 1974 (Folder 56.894)
  - MARYOTT, Margaret
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 56.895)
  - MASSEE, May